Change begins with a whisper.
The Help is a drama film directed by Tate Taylor.
Aibileen Clark is a middle-aged African-American maid who has spent her life raising white children and has recently lost her only son; Minny Jackson is an African-American maid who has often offended her employers despite her family's
struggles with money and her desperate need for jobs; and Eugenia "Skeeter" Phelan is a young white woman who has recently moved back home after graduating college to find out her childhood maid has mysteriously disappeared.
These three stories intertwine to explain how life in Jackson, Mississippi revolves around "the
help"; yet they are always kept at a certain distance because of racial lines.
Skeeter Phelan, played by Emma Stone.
Aibileen Clark, played by Viola Davis.
Hilly Holbrook, played by Bryce Dallas Howard.
Minny Jackson, played by Octavia Spencer.
Celia Foote, played by Jessica Chastain.
Elizabeth Leefolt, played by Ahna O'Reilly.
The Help is a 2011 period drama film written and directed by Tate Taylor,
and based on Kathryn Stockett's 2009 novel of the same name.
The film features an ensemble cast, including Emma Stone, Viola Davis, Bryce Dallas Howard,
Octavia Spencer, Jessica Chastain, Allison Janney, Cicely Tyson, and Sissy Spacek.
The film and novel recount the story of a young white woman and
aspiring journalist Eugenia "Skeeter" Phelan.
The story focuses on her relationship with two black maids, Aibileen Clark and Minny
Jackson, during the civil rights movement in 1963 Jackson, Mississippi.
In an attempt to become a legitimate journalist and writer, Skeeter decides to write a book from the point of view
of the maids, exposing the racism and discrimination they face as they work for white families.
Black domestic workers in 1960s United States were referred to as "the help", hence the
eponymous title of the journalistic exposé, the novel, and the film.
DreamWorks Pictures acquired the screen rights to Stockett's novel in March 2010 and quickly
commissioned the film with Chris Columbus, Michael Barnathan, and Brunson Green as producers.
The film's casting began later that month, with principal
photography following four months after in Mississippi.
The film is an international co-production between companies based in
the United States, India, and the United Arab Emirates.
The Help premiered at the Jackson suburb of Madison, Mississippi, on July 30, 2011, and at Beverly Hills on August 9, 2011, and went into general theatrical
release in North America on August 10, 2011, with distribution by Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures through the Touchstone Pictures label.
The film was a critical and commercial success, grossing $221.8 million
worldwide and receiving generally positive reviews from critics.
The Help received four Academy Award nominations including Best Picture, Best Actress for Davis, and
Best Supporting Actress for both Chastain and Spencer, with Spencer winning the award.
The film also won the Screen Actors Guild Award for
Outstanding Performance by a Cast in a Motion Picture.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, mississippi
river, exploitation, racial segregation, racism.
The tone is emotional.